

# Alexander Alexandrov

contact@alexandrov.cc | +359-888-365-076 | LinkedIn | GitHub

#### Tech Skills

React, Java, JavaScript/TypeScript, Rust, HTML, CSS, Vercel AI SDK, AWS JavaScript SDK, PostgreSQL, Spring MVC, Next.is.

#### Soft Skills

Empathy, communication, teamwork, helpfulness, patience, problem solving, accountability.

# Experience

Proxiad SEE Sofia, Bulgaria

Full-stack Developer Aug 2023 - Present

Working on various projects, primarily focusing on the front-end side, using React, JavaScript/TypeScript, Java, HTML, and SCSS.

**DXC Technology** Sofia, Bulgaria

Full-stack Developer Apr 2020 - Aug 2023

Working on various projects using React, JavaScript/TypeScript, Rust, Java, Amazon Web Services, Terraform, Spring MVC, PostgreSQL, iBATIS, and Material UI.

CamplightSofia, BulgariaWeb Developer InternSep 2019 - Apr 2020

Developing a web application using React, JavaScript/TypeScript, Next.js,

HTML, Material UI, and GraphQL.

#### Education

Camplight
MaxPlus
Sofia University "St. Kliment Ohridski"
University of Forestry
High School of Mathematics

React Fundamentals
Java Fundamentals
PhD in Theology
Master of Engineering
Mathematics

#### Certifications

Oracle Certified Associate, Java SE 8 Programmer

Jan 2019

## Spoken Languages

Bulgarian - native, English - C1, Italian - B2, Russian - B1, Greek - A2

### Summary

I am a software developer with a passion for learning and turning creative ideas into practical software solutions. With experience in full-stack engineering, I stay updated on the latest technologies and design patterns. I enjoy solving tech challenges and working in team settings, where I value input and contribute to a positive, communicative atmosphere.